<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hugo on Appernetic.io</title>
    <link>/tags/hugo/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hugo on Appernetic.io</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-EN</language>
    <managingEditor>support@appernetic.io (Admin)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>support@appernetic.io (Admin)</webMaster>
    <copyright>(c) 2016 Appernetic.io</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2016 05:53:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/hugo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>How to set up a static hugo website on github pages in 2 minutes</title>
      <link>/2016/04/09/how-to-set-up-a-static-hugo-website-on-github-pages-in-2-minutes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2016 05:53:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>support@appernetic.io (Admin)</author>
      <guid>/2016/04/09/how-to-set-up-a-static-hugo-website-on-github-pages-in-2-minutes/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://res.cloudinary.com/appernetic/v1460186011/k1seurwnwzitp8tbchvx&#34; alt=&#34;A static website - appernetic.io&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;A static website is fast and secure but it is not easy to set up a new blog or website if you don&amp;rsquo;t know a lot of commands, tools and also how to install them when you would rather like to be writing exciting content to distribute over the intermingling webz!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First you have to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;download the right version of the static site generator for your OS and architecture.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;install git&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;create a GitHub, Bitbucket, Dropbox or Amazon S3 account or set-up a web server with a web Host.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then when the installation and configuration are ready there are lots of steps to just have the website up and running on the Interwebz.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I created Appernetic I had to do all these 17 steps in the terminal after installation and configuration :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;hugo new site blog 
cd blog
hugo new post/easy-peasy.MD
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then open the file in a text editor and  write content, then dive back in to terminal:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;mkdir themes 
cd themes 
git clone https://github.com/appernetic/hugo-bootstrap.git
hugo undraft content/post/easy-peasy.md
hugo --theme=hugo-bootstrap
mkdir blog-public
cd blog-public
git init
git remote add origin https://easypeasy:236102a7cf231y2a5084a4847e0de99e636e391c@github.com/easypeasy
cp -r ../blog/public/ .
git add --all
git commit -am ”Publish site”
git push origin master
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have just published your first blog! Check your live server at:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; http://easypeasy.github.io (do not click this is just an example)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All these 17 steps will take at least 30 min if you have the knowledge. Now we do the same with Appernetic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We assume the following is already done:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You have signed up for a subscription.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You have created a GitHub account.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Now watch this instructive how-to video for 2:13 minutes.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//player.vimeo.com/video/162159974&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-about-custom-domains&#34;&gt;What about custom domains?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt; No problem, it is easy to connect your custom domain to your GitHub Pages. Follow these five steps (no programming or terminal console needed):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In your Appernetic dashboard, Sync you appernetic project with GitHub, this will create a appernetic-hugo-project with all your files on GitHub. We do this so that we can work with files outside the content folder.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Place this file in your GitHub, appernetic-hugo-project repositories static folder:
Filename: CNAME&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;blog.easypeasy.com
Here you can see how &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/appernetic/appernetic-hugo-project-1/blob/master/static/CNAME&#34;&gt;we did this&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sync your project again in your Appernetic Dashboard.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Publish your blog (if you have something un-drafted to publish). Now your CNAME file also lives in the compiled GitHub Pages site.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now the last step is to make it work over the Internet. For this, you have to make a CNAME record in your DNS or your service providers DNS and wait for everything to propagate  (give it 8 to 24 hours). Read more: &lt;a href=&#34;https://help.github.com/articles/using-a-custom-domain-with-github-pages/&#34;&gt;using a custom domain with GitHub pages&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s it! Give fast, secure blogging a try and you will never go back to WordPress, Joomla or Drupal. We support you both in Swedish and English.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>