<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Static Website on Appernetic.io blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.appernetic.io/topics/static-website/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Static Website on Appernetic.io blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-EN</language>
    <managingEditor>support@appernetic.io (Admin)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>support@appernetic.io (Admin)</webMaster>
    <copyright>(c) 2016 Appernetic.io</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 May 2016 18:04:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blog.appernetic.io/topics/static-website/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Appernetic theme showcase gallery</title>
      <link>https://blog.appernetic.io/2016/05/27/appernetic-theme-showcase-gallery/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2016 18:04:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>support@appernetic.io (Admin)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.appernetic.io/2016/05/27/appernetic-theme-showcase-gallery/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://res.cloudinary.com/appernetic/v1464414173/suli8vdkjsw9luw1ol3f&#34; alt=&#34;Setup wizard, now with theme showcase gallery in appernetic dashboard&#34; /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The theme showcase gallery is ready! Now you can browse the gallery and install a theme just by clicking on it. This is the themes listed at &lt;a href=&#34;http://themes.gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo Theme Showcase&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;aggregated-meta-information&#34;&gt;Aggregated meta information&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We automatically aggregate and build a JSON file each week that contains the extracted meta information from each of the 86 themes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also check if each theme has an exampleSite folder and a config.toml file and if they have we give them a star in the frontend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything is served as a JSON file from a REST API endpoint, then we have Angular mangling the arrays and objects to make them look intelligible to us humans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are not the most patient type of person, avoid themes that have no star, they  need some extra attention to get your website working.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Included in each theme listing is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;List item&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thumbnail image&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Theme name&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Description&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Author (with website URL)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Repository link&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Minimum Hugo version (which the theme works with).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Licence&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Features/Tags (blue and green labels)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the aggregated meta information and the themes gallery ready it was now also possible to include the one-click theme install feature in the quick start wizard.  This will make it much easier to get started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://res.cloudinary.com/appernetic/v1464371347/mgc1lnbrytafkitsjmma&#34; alt=&#34;Theme showcase gallery item in appernetic dashboard&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Click on the dashboard link up to the right and see for yourself and build a &lt;a href=&#34;https://appernetic.io/app/#/dashboard/list/create&#34;&gt;static website&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://res.cloudinary.com/appernetic/v1464415618/eiysait32vipexfyhduh&#34; alt=&#34;Theme showcase gallery item in appernetic dashboard&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the way, I have just removed Twitter user sign-in. It was an easy decision. Twitter users had no email in their meta info and was lagging behind in the interwebs, and behaved inconsistently. Also, I had no Twitter freemium or paying users and I had exceeded Auth0&amp;rsquo;s social connection limits anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to set up a static Hugo website on GitHub pages in 2 minutes</title>
      <link>https://blog.appernetic.io/2016/04/09/how-to-set-up-a-static-hugo-website-on-github-pages-in-2-minutes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2016 05:53:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>support@appernetic.io (Admin)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.appernetic.io/2016/04/09/how-to-set-up-a-static-hugo-website-on-github-pages-in-2-minutes/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://res.cloudinary.com/appernetic/v1460186011/k1seurwnwzitp8tbchvx&#34; alt=&#34;A static website - appernetic.io&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;A static website is fast and secure but it is not easy to set up a new blog or website if you don&amp;rsquo;t know a lot of commands, tools and also how to install them when you would rather like to be writing exciting content to distribute over the interwebz!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First,​ you have to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;download the right version of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://appernetic.io&#34;&gt;static website generator&lt;/a&gt; for your OS and architecture.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;install git&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;create a GitHub, Bitbucket, Dropbox or Amazon S3 account or set-up a web server with a web Host.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then when the installation and configuration are ready there are lots of steps to just have the website up and running on the Interwebz.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I created Appernetic I had to do all these 15 steps in the terminal after installation and configuration :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;hugo new site blog 
cd blog
hugo new post/easy-peasy.MD
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then open the file in a text editor and  write content, then dive back in to terminal:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;mkdir themes 
cd themes 
git clone https://github.com/appernetic/hugo-bootstrap.git
hugo undraft content/post/easy-peasy.md
hugo --theme=hugo-bootstrap
mkdir blog-public
cd blog-public
git init
git remote add origin https://easypeasy:236102a7cf231y2a5084a4847e0de99e636e391c@github.com/easypeasy
cp -r ../blog/public/ .
git add --all
git commit -am ”Publish site”
git push origin master
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have just published your first blog! Check your live server at:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; http://easypeasy.github.io (do not click this is just an example)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All these 15 steps will take at least 30 min if you have the knowledge. Now we do the same with Appernetic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We assume the following is already done:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You have signed up for a subscription.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You have created a GitHub account.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Now watch this instructive how-to video for 2:13 minutes.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//player.vimeo.com/video/162159974&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-about-custom-domains&#34;&gt;What about custom domains?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No problem, it is easy to connect your custom domain to your GitHub Pages. Follow these five steps (no programming or terminal console needed):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In your Appernetic dashboard, Sync you appernetic project with GitHub, this will create a appernetic-hugo-project with all your files on GitHub. We do this so that we can work with files outside the content folder.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Place this file in your GitHub, appernetic-hugo-project repositories static folder:
Filename: CNAME&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;blog.easypeasy.com
Here you can see how &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/appernetic/appernetic-hugo-project-1/blob/master/static/CNAME&#34;&gt;we did this&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sync your project again in your Appernetic Dashboard.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Publish your blog (if you have something un-drafted to publish). Now your CNAME file also lives in the compiled GitHub Pages site.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now the last step is to make it work over the Internet. For this, you have to make a CNAME record in your DNS or your service providers DNS and wait for everything to propagate  (give it 8 to 24 hours). Read more: &lt;a href=&#34;https://help.github.com/articles/using-a-custom-domain-with-github-pages/&#34;&gt;using a custom domain with GitHub pages&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s it! &lt;a href=&#34;https://appernetic.io&#34;&gt;Give fast, secure blogging a try&lt;/a&gt; and you will never go back to WordPress, Joomla or Drupal. We support you both in Swedish and English.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collaborating and working with hugo themes</title>
      <link>https://blog.appernetic.io/2016/02/18/collaborating-and-working-with-hugo-themes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2016 20:27:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>support@appernetic.io (Admin)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.appernetic.io/2016/02/18/collaborating-and-working-with-hugo-themes/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;customizing-themes:ac4cc3988a245fe44051722c4a01ffd6&#34;&gt;Customizing themes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you just have set up your Appernetic &lt;a href=&#34;https://appernetic.io&#34;&gt;static website service&lt;/a&gt; account you need to add a theme. The easiest way is to clone a theme which you can do from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://appernetic.io/app/#/dashboard/list/themes&#34;&gt;menu button&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://res.cloudinary.com/appernetic/v1457304135/pig3qgwntchbkk0x9tab&#34; alt=&#34;Install a theme&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can start by cloning my customized &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/appernetic/hugo-bootstrap-mod.git&#34;&gt;hugo-bootstrap theme&lt;/a&gt; or get one from &lt;a href=&#34;http://themes.gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;. Then select the theme from the list of themes and click Use Theme. When you do that the theme config settings will be copied to your project folder. Now open the settings tab and change the settings as you would like to have it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can change the bootswatch to another design by changing the theme = &amp;laquo;paper&amp;raquo; under [params].&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the different bootswatch designs you can use:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cerulean&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cosmo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cyborg&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;darkly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;default&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;flatly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;journal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;lumen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;paper&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;readable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sandstone&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;simplex&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;slate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;spacelab&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;superhero&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;united&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;yeti&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are lots of themes at &lt;a href=&#34;http://themes.gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;, but you probably want to customize the theme before you use it so that you have a blog with  a theme that is matching your business website or service. I am using Bootswatch Paper theme for &lt;a href=&#34;https://appernetic.io&#34;&gt;Appernetic static website service&lt;/a&gt;. Fortunately, I found &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mmrath/hugo-bootstrap&#34;&gt;hugo-bootstrap&lt;/a&gt; and cloned it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://res.cloudinary.com/appernetic/v1464371347/mgc1lnbrytafkitsjmma&#34; alt=&#34;enter image description here&#34; /&gt;
Now you can also browse the &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.appernetic.io/2016/05/27/appernetic-theme-showcase-gallery/&#34;&gt;theme showcase gallery&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then to customize it further I pressed the &lt;strong&gt;Sync&lt;/strong&gt; button which does a pull and then a push to your Appernetic project repository at &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; with the name &lt;strong&gt;appernetic-hugo-project&lt;/strong&gt; . When you start out you will not have this repo so it is automatically created for you and all strange git commands is hidden away so you do not have to think about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you start out you will not have this repo so it is automatically
created for you and all strange git commands is hidden away so you do
not have to think about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://res.cloudinary.com/appernetic/v1457304341/htdhjub2yfcw4bpkzklw&#34; alt=&#34;Sync with GitHub&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now to work with the theme I did a pull to my local computer, edited the theme with my favorite editor &lt;em&gt;Atom&lt;/em&gt; and after that I did a commit and a push back to my GitHub project repo. If you are a hard-core git user you would start terminal and add the commands. There is also a very easy to use desktop client for &lt;a href=&#34;https://desktop.github.com/&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://res.cloudinary.com/appernetic/v1457304455/tdsbe75348lm3dxa1csw&#34; alt=&#34;GitHub Desktop app&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;collaborating:ac4cc3988a245fe44051722c4a01ffd6&#34;&gt;Collaborating&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notice also that I have all the social and collaborating features in GitHub so I can invite a real front end designer to have a look at my attempts to customize the theme. My last step is to do a &lt;strong&gt;Sync&lt;/strong&gt; again in Appernetic and then a &lt;strong&gt;Publish&lt;/strong&gt; and after 10 min all is live on &lt;a href=&#34;https://appernetic.github.io/&#34;&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notice also that I have all the social and collaborating features in
GitHub so I can invite a real front end designer to have a look at my
attempts to customize the theme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;start-blogging:ac4cc3988a245fe44051722c4a01ffd6&#34;&gt;Start blogging!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From now on it is very easy to start blogging. Select the &lt;strong&gt;post&lt;/strong&gt; directory in the tree view, it is where blog post lives. Create a new file,  name it with a headline, it will be sluggified automatically. Select &lt;em&gt;TOML&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;YAML&lt;/em&gt; front matter (TOML as default selection). The file tree will be updated and show the new file. Open the file and blog away! Turn on auto save and all text you write will be saved every other minute. Remember to &lt;strong&gt;undraft&lt;/strong&gt; the post if you would like to see it after publishing and  add key words, tags, and topics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://res.cloudinary.com/appernetic/v1457304529/clqxr6v6xhxum0jvqabz&#34; alt=&#34;Start blogging&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy blogging!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tip, skip the first headline in the post (at least in hugo-bootstrap it will be added automatically) and edit the &lt;em&gt;front matter&lt;/em&gt; located at the bottom of the editor after the preview and switch the first letter in the title to capital.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>