<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Appernetic Service on Appernetic.io blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.appernetic.io/tags/appernetic-service/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Appernetic Service on Appernetic.io blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-EN</language>
    <managingEditor>support@appernetic.io (Admin)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>support@appernetic.io (Admin)</webMaster>
    <copyright>(c) 2017 Appernetic.io</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2016 13:10:05 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.appernetic.io/tags/appernetic-service/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Now you can sign in with twitter, facebook, github or your e-mail!</title>
      <link>https://blog.appernetic.io/2016/04/26/now-you-can-sign-in-with-twitter-facebook-and-github/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2016 13:10:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>support@appernetic.io (Admin)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.appernetic.io/2016/04/26/now-you-can-sign-in-with-twitter-facebook-and-github/</guid>
      <description>Static website service update! After users having expressed concerns about privacy we contemplated the implications over the weekend what impact it would have to add a custom sign up and log in with e-mail and a user-generated password to the static website service.
For us and the service there is the problem with:
 Users that are not verified signing up Maintaining a user database Users that are not following GitHub Pages policy Sending out verification e-mail to users Developing and testing  Everything has a cost.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minor enhancements and fixes</title>
      <link>https://blog.appernetic.io/2016/03/14/minor-enhancements-and-fixes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2016 07:06:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>support@appernetic.io (Admin)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.appernetic.io/2016/03/14/minor-enhancements-and-fixes/</guid>
      <description>Site preview fixes and enhancements There was a case of a very sticky cache and this doesn&amp;rsquo;t work well if you immediately would want to check changes. Site preview has also been moved to its own subdomain: preview.appernetic.io, and now it is also possible to view the site preview if you are not signed in, so it is easier to share the URL and collaborate.
If you are experiencing problems such as site preview URL goes to a page that does not exist, try clearing the cache in your browser.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Manage your web site images in the cloud</title>
      <link>https://blog.appernetic.io/2016/03/09/manage-your-web-site-images-in-the-cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2016 14:28:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>support@appernetic.io (Admin)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.appernetic.io/2016/03/09/manage-your-web-site-images-in-the-cloud/</guid>
      <description>Cloudinary for image and video assets management in your static website We no longer use GitHub to manage images in your Appernetic static website service account. You can still use GitHub and they have an easy to use image upload, but to use Appernetic&amp;rsquo;s image upload you now have to first create a Cloudinary account. The advantages of using Cloudinary is so big that it was an easy decision to integrate it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Performance optimization</title>
      <link>https://blog.appernetic.io/2016/03/08/performance-optimization/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 19:03:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>support@appernetic.io (Admin)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.appernetic.io/2016/03/08/performance-optimization/</guid>
      <description>Static website service performance improvements We have made significant performance improvements in our static website service and have dug deep into everything on the client and server side. All images are now sent with Cloudinary&amp;rsquo;s Akamai CDN including the favicon, and every CSS, HTML and Javascript file are compressed and minified.
Speed Index We use webpagetest for our performance tests. As a measure of how one experiences the web page speed we use Speed Index.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>