<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Static Web Site Generator on Appernetic.io</title>
    <link>https://appernetic.github.io/topics/static-web-site-generator/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Static Web Site Generator on Appernetic.io</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-EN</language>
    <managingEditor>support@appernetic.io (Admin)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>support@appernetic.io (Admin)</webMaster>
    <copyright>(c) 2016 Appernetic.io</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2016 19:50:09 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://appernetic.github.io/topics/static-web-site-generator/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Why use a static web site generator?</title>
      <link>https://appernetic.github.io/2016/02/10/why-use-a-static-web-site-generator/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2016 19:50:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>support@appernetic.io (Admin)</author>
      <guid>https://appernetic.github.io/2016/02/10/why-use-a-static-web-site-generator/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;full-circle:f405389e24819888f4339a200bcc1557&#34;&gt;Full circle&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today we have come full circle with static site generators. A long time ago at the end of 1994 I built a static web site for the Swedish Tourist Association that contained hundreds of handcrafted html pages, it was quite advanced with a email to fax gateway that sent out bookings to remote mountain stations. Then I found ColdFusion in the beginning of 1995 and the the sites I built had dynamic content served from MS Access databases. Later I started to use mySQL and built my own hosted CMS that was easily updated by non-technical users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-programmable-web:f405389e24819888f4339a200bcc1557&#34;&gt;The programmable web&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a lot of things to manage, servers, operating systems, security patches, databases, backup and on the application level with different versions and dependencies. Then I moved on to Platform as a Service (PaaS) and I only needed to manage and secure my applications, databases was now managed by a BaaS (backend as a service) and if I needed something specific such as commenting, search, email service or calendar there was always an API to connect to. The programmable web was born.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;advantage-static-site-generators:f405389e24819888f4339a200bcc1557&#34;&gt;Advantage static site generators&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now there is a rich ecosystem of service providers for anything including forms, calendars, content, images, email, e-commerce etc. A dynamic CMS is no longer the best option for a web site. There is rely only a need for dynamic web sites if you have a very large site with a complex structure and rich content such as news sites and large enterprises that have content that is updated very frequently. With a static site generator you didn’t really lose anything of practical value. Instead you have several advantages with a static site such as:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fast&lt;/strong&gt;, static files can be served fast. There is no database or templating layer that slows requests down. A static site will always be the fastest way to deliver content.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Secure&lt;/strong&gt;, static sites do not contain dynamic content, and are therefore immune to most common attacks that dynamic systems like Wordpress and Joomla are plagued with (more than 70% of today’s WordPress installations are vulnerable to known exploits).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Previewable&lt;/strong&gt;, It is easy to separate preview from the live site.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Versioning&lt;/strong&gt;, static site generators store their content in flat text files. This makes them ideal to be used with version control systems, such as Git.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Appernetic we are building a static web generator as a service that is easy to use for non-technical users and add some extra value. To start with we have included an easy to use editor, visual tree view, image upload, site preview, continuous integration with GitHub, auto save and theme cloning.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>