<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Appernetic Static Site Generator on Appernetic.io blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.appernetic.io/tags/appernetic-static-site-generator/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Appernetic Static Site Generator on Appernetic.io blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-EN</language>
    <managingEditor>support@appernetic.io (Admin)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>support@appernetic.io (Admin)</webMaster>
    <copyright>(c) 2017 Appernetic.io</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2016 13:10:05 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.appernetic.io/tags/appernetic-static-site-generator/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Now you can sign in with twitter, facebook, github or your e-mail!</title>
      <link>https://blog.appernetic.io/2016/04/26/now-you-can-sign-in-with-twitter-facebook-and-github/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2016 13:10:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>support@appernetic.io (Admin)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.appernetic.io/2016/04/26/now-you-can-sign-in-with-twitter-facebook-and-github/</guid>
      <description>Static website service update! After users having expressed concerns about privacy we contemplated the implications over the weekend what impact it would have to add a custom sign up and log in with e-mail and a user-generated password to the static website service.
For us and the service there is the problem with:
 Users that are not verified signing up Maintaining a user database Users that are not following GitHub Pages policy Sending out verification e-mail to users Developing and testing  Everything has a cost.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Manage your web site images in the cloud</title>
      <link>https://blog.appernetic.io/2016/03/09/manage-your-web-site-images-in-the-cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2016 14:28:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>support@appernetic.io (Admin)</author>
      <guid>https://blog.appernetic.io/2016/03/09/manage-your-web-site-images-in-the-cloud/</guid>
      <description>Cloudinary for image and video assets management in your static website We no longer use GitHub to manage images in your Appernetic static website service account. You can still use GitHub and they have an easy to use image upload, but to use Appernetic&amp;rsquo;s image upload you now have to first create a Cloudinary account. The advantages of using Cloudinary is so big that it was an easy decision to integrate it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>